{"test_questions": [[{"question": "The yeast generated during the fermentation of beer is generally separated by", "opta": "centrifugation", "optb": "filtration", "optc": "cell disruption", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Final alcohol content in wine varies from", "opta": "6-9 % by weight", "optb": "8-13 % by weight", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "13-15 % by weight", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the desirable sugar content of the grapes required for the wine production?", "opta": "2-5%", "optb": "5-10%", "optc": "10-14%", "optd": "14-20%", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is true for the ale beer?", "opta": "Top yeast of S cerevisiae is used", "optb": "Fermentation is quick and completes in 5-7 days", "optc": "Quantity of hops used is more than in lager beer", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Bock beer is prepared from", "opta": "roasted germinated barley seeds", "optb": "rice", "optc": "wheat", "optd": "grapes", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Sherry is a type of", "opta": "wine", "optb": "beer", "optc": "brandy", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is not the purpose of punching down?", "opta": "To oxidize the wine", "optb": "To extract tannin", "optc": "To reduce possible microbial spoilage", "optd": "To keep the cap moist", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The term Racking refers to", "opta": "stacking unlabeled wine in bins for aging", "optb": "adding yeast to initiate fermentation", "optc": "storing hoses to drain on a slanted board", "optd": "removing clear liquid from sediment", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The process of making malt as soluble as possible by using enzymes adjuncts etc is known as", "opta": "brewing", "optb": "malting", "optc": "mashing", "optd": "pitching", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Chaptalization is", "opta": "adding sucrose to must", "optb": "adding grape juice to must", "optc": "adding sugar to wine before bottling", "optd": "adding grape juice to wine before bottling", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The crystal-like material sometimes found in wine bottles is", "opta": "residual diatomaceous earth", "optb": "tannin", "optc": "prevented by cold stabilizing", "optd": "caused by excessive malic acid", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Lagers are the beer in which fermentation is carried out using", "opta": "top yeast", "optb": "bottom yeast", "optc": "either of these", "optd": "middle yeast", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Sake is", "opta": "rice beer or wine of India", "optb": "wheat beer or wine", "optc": "barley beer or wine", "optd": "rice beer or wine of Japan", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Volatile acidity is", "opta": "also known as total acidity", "optb": "produced by acetobacter", "optc": "produced by Brettanomyces", "optd": "known for producing a mousy or barnyard aroma", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Grist is", "opta": "coarse powder obtained after milling of malted barley", "optb": "an aqueous extract of malt", "optc": "malted barley", "optd": "coagulated protein obtained during boiling", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the malolactic fermentation is not carried out,", "opta": "the wine will have an odd odor", "optb": "malic acid may precipitate, leaving small crystals", "optc": "the wine may be microbially unstable", "optd": "the wine will be too low in acid", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following organism is used for the fermentation of grapes?", "opta": "Rhizopus sonti", "optb": "Aspergillus oryzae", "optc": "Lactobacillus vermiformis", "optd": "Saccharomyces cerevisiae", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Wort is", "opta": "an aqueous extract of malt", "optb": "malted barley", "optc": "coagulated protein obtained during boiling", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is not correct about blush wines?", "opta": "They are stored in barrels", "optb": "They are bottled within a year", "optc": "They are usually slightly sweet", "optd": "They are fermented in stainless steel", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Malting process allows malt amylase and proteinases to degrade starch and protein to", "opta": "glucose and peptone as well as peptides", "optb": "glucose and amino acids", "optc": "maltose and peptone as well as peptides", "optd": "maltose and amino acids", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is true for the lager beer?", "opta": "Bottom fermenting yeast is used for the preparation", "optb": "Top yeast is used for the preparation", "optc": "Require high fermentation temperature", "optd": "Both (b) and (c)", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The germination of barley kernels under controlled temperature and humidity to generate enzymes for the degradation of starch and protein is known as", "opta": "brewing", "optb": "malting", "optc": "mashing", "optd": "pitching", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Fining a wine is defined as", "opta": "adding one substance to remove another", "optb": "removing small particles", "optc": "adding acid", "optd": "removing tannin", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Malolactic fermentation", "opta": "produces lactic acid", "optb": "reduces total acidity", "optc": "produces diacetyl", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What temperature is maintained during anaerobic fermentation of red wine?", "opta": "20-24 \u00b0C", "optb": "24-27 \u00b0C", "optc": "27-31 \u00b0C", "optd": "31-34 \u00b0C", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Wine is obtained after alcoholic fermentation of", "opta": "rice", "optb": "wheat", "optc": "grapes", "optd": "barley", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "After storage and recarbonation, left over yeast is separated by", "opta": "centrifugation", "optb": "filtration", "optc": "cell disruption", "optd": "need not to be separated", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Sodium or potassium meta bi sulphate is added to crushed grapes to", "opta": "enhance the flavouring compound", "optb": "check the undesirable organisms", "optc": "maintain pH", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A hydrometer", "opta": "measures wine acid", "optb": "requires a few drops of juice", "optc": "measures alcohol in the wine", "optd": "measures grape sugar", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Punching down is done", "opta": "for the same reasons as pumping over", "optb": "to extract tannin", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "to keep the cap dry", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Maturation of the beers is carried out at", "opta": "14\u00b0C", "optb": "10\u00b0C", "optc": "6\u00b0C", "optd": "2\u00b0C", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The dried malt is the source of", "opta": "amylase", "optb": "proteinases", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "cellulase", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a hot climate, grapes lose acidity because", "opta": "enough tartaric acid is not made", "optb": "enough malic acid is not made", "optc": "of break down of malic acid", "optd": "of break down of tartaric acid", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What temperature is maintained during anaerobic fermentation of white wine?", "opta": "10-21 \u00b0C", "optb": "21-30 \u00b0C", "optc": "30-35 \u00b0C", "optd": "15-25 \u00b0C", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Ales are the beer in which fermentation is carried out using", "opta": "top yeast", "optb": "bottom yeast", "optc": "either of the above", "optd": "middle yeast", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How long does it take to complete fermentation process in case of red wine?", "opta": "1-3 days", "optb": "3-5 days", "optc": "5-7 days", "optd": "7-11 days", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In sparkling wine production, the cuvee is", "opta": "the wire cage that holds the cork in place", "optb": "the sugar addition just before corking", "optc": "the sugar/yeast addition to the base wine", "optd": "the base wine", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The organism used for the preparation of sake is", "opta": "Rhizopus sonti", "optb": "Aspergillus oryzae", "optc": "Lactobacillus vermiformis", "optd": "Saccharomyces pyriformis", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The organism used for the preparation of sonti is", "opta": "Rhizopus sonti", "optb": "Aspergillus oryzae", "optc": "Lactobacillus vermiformis", "optd": "Saccharomyces pyriformis", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Sonti is", "opta": "rice beer or wine of India", "optb": "wheat beer or wine", "optc": "barley beer or wine", "optd": "rice beer or wine of Japan", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Carbonic maceration wines", "opta": "are made from crushed grapes", "optb": "are very fruity white wines", "optc": "are produced in California", "optd": "are low tannin red wines", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If a winemaker wanted to make a deeply colored red wine, which of the following should not be done?", "opta": "Bleed off juice prior to fermenting on skins", "optb": "Ferment at a high temperature", "optc": "Use whole clusters", "optd": "Punch down at least once a day", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Alcohol content of sake varies from", "opta": "1-5 %", "optb": "4-17 %", "optc": "17-25%", "optd": "more than 25%", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Wort is boiled with the hops", "opta": "to help in protein coagulation", "optb": "to provide bitter taste and flavour to the beer", "optc": "to help in the coagulation of tannins", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Wine yeast", "opta": "is sensitive to sulphur di oxide", "optb": "is resistant to sulphur di oxide", "optc": "shows enhanced enzyme production in presence of sulphur di oxide", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How long does it take to complete fermentation process in case of white wine?", "opta": "1-3 days", "optb": "3-5 days", "optc": "5-7 days", "optd": "7-11 days", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which type of press produces the most high quality juice or wine?", "opta": "Membrane press", "optb": "Continuous press", "optc": "Vertical basket press", "optd": "Horizontal basket press", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The crushed grapes are known as", "opta": "malt", "optb": "must", "optc": "wort", "optd": "sonti", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}